welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video we're going to be
在这段视频中 我们将成为
playing with some more effects and kind
玩一些更多的效果和亲切
of just doing some fun effects in this
在这里面做一些有趣的效果
one we have some music down here that I
一 我们这里有一些音乐 我
recorded in from the classic NES video
录制自经典的NES视频
game contra let's play that a little bit
游戏反差 让我们来玩一玩
and see what it sounds like
看看这听起来像什么
and this is actually a kind of a looping
这实际上是一种循环
so if we go if we click up here this
所以如果我们点击这里
will show us just kind of the extents
将会向我们展示出
from the start to the finish so it's 25
从开始到结束 一共是25
seconds long it's meant to be a looping
几秒钟的时间 这意味着它是一个循环
piece so right here at changes it has
一件就在这里 它有很多变化
like two different kind of phrases it
就像是两种不同的短语
goes into this phrase and then at the
进入这个短语 然后在
end is supposed to loop back to the
End应该循环回到
start here so this is we're supposed to
从这里开始 这是我们应该做的
loop back so if we select the whole
循环返回 因此如果我们选择整个
thing we can actually go to effect and
我们实际上可以实施的事情
we can go to repeat and then it says how
我们可以重复一遍 然后它会告诉我们
many times do you want to repeat we'll
你想重复几遍吗？我们会
just say 1 and we go ok and what that
只要说1 我们就好了 然后呢
does is it actually attached it
它真的附在上面了吗？
basically did a copy and paste it copied
基本上是复制并粘贴复制的内容
this whole selection then it pasted it
这整个选择然后它粘贴了它
again at the end here so we can now our
在这里的末尾 我们现在可以
cut our whole song is 50 seconds long
剪掉我们的整首歌有50秒长
and we can play and see what the the
我们可以一起玩 看看是什么
overlap part sounds like or where it
重叠部分听起来像或在哪里
repeats so I'm gonna zoom in there
重复 所以我要把它放大
because it's just a little bit we have a
因为这只是我们的一小部分
little bit of silence there where it's a
在那里有一点沉默 那里是一个
little hiccup where it's repeating so
它在重复的地方有点小问题所以
let's go back where was it at right here
让我们回去看看它是在哪里就在这里
I mean I select that a little bit and
我是说 我选择了一点 然后
hit delete so we don't have much of a
点击删除 这样我们就不会有太多
drop you know even I'm just to get rid
丢掉你知道 即使我只是想摆脱
of all that little line there and I
在那条小路上 我和
think now I should just go right into it
现在我想我应该直接投入进去
maybe it's a little bit too much there
可能有点太多了
about this
关于这件事
yeah a little bit of a hiccup but it's
是的 有一点小问题 但这是
okay so we go let's now if we go to the
好的 我们现在就去 如果我们去
full extent we see this we kind of
我们完全可以看到这一点 我们可以说
recognized as it's happening twice
公认为它正在发生两次
actually born me and ooh I'm gonna go
生来就是我 我要走了
ctrl Z ctrl Z and I'm gonna undo that
Ctrl Z Ctrl Z和我要撤销
part because we're gonna be applying
部分是因为我们要申请
some filters to this or some different
一些滤镜到这个或一些不同的
effects to it that's gonna take a little
对它的影响需要一点时间
bit of time to process so the shorter it
需要一点时间来处理 所以时间越短
is the better okay is we could have
是不是更好的是我们本可以
effects let's do so we have just like
效果让我们这样做 我们就像
Reverse if we reverse it
如果我们反转 就反转
[Music]
[音乐]
it sounds okay right
听起来不错 对吧？
doesn't sound that much different
听起来没什么不同
because this is just like electronic
因为这就像是电子产品
instruments creating this so I'll do
乐器创造了这一切 所以我会这样做
ctrl Z we can go to effects so we can do
Ctrl Z我们可以转到Effect 这样我们就可以
a fade in and fade out the way that
一个淡入淡出的方式
works if we select whatever part we have
如果我们选择我们拥有的任何部件 都会起作用
selected will be the fade so if I want
所选内容将会淡出 所以如果我想
to fade in over the first two seconds I
在前两秒淡入我的视线
just select from zero to two seconds I
只需选择0到2秒I
go to effects fade in and if I want to
转到效果淡入 如果我想
fade out I just select the last maybe
淡出 我只是选择了最后一个可能
let's do the last three seconds and then
让我们做最后三秒钟 然后
go effects fade out source net and now
Go效果淡出源码网络 现在
this will fade in and out so we go to
这将淡入淡出 因此我们将转到
the beginning
一开始
[Music]
[音乐]
and then when we get to the end it'll
然后当我们走到最后的时候
fade out very nice did I ever show you
淡出很好我有没有给你看过
like with it how the scrubbing works if
就像它的擦洗工作原理一样 如果
we click up here when we have a screen
当我们有屏幕时 我们点击此处
triangle just click it starts playing
三角形只需点击即可开始播放
and it will actually go wherever we
它实际上会到达我们所在的任何地方
supply so we can click and drag a part
提供 以便我们可以点击并拖动部件
up here with some arrows and it'll just
上面有几支箭 它就会
play that selection rather than actually
播放该选择 而不是实际
having to select it like this we can
必须这样选择它 我们才能
actually left click up here and draw and
实际上 左键点击这里 画出
it'll play wherever we can it whatever
它会在我们可以播放的任何地方播放
wherever we tell it to and if we click
无论我们告诉它去哪里 如果我们点击
up in between here so there's a triangle
在这里的中间有一个三角形
if we click up here to get these two
如果我们点击这里让这两个人
triangles it'll actually follow our
它实际上会跟随我们的
mouse cursor and play kind of like
鼠标光标和玩法有点像
scrubbing it'll scrub in the direction
擦洗它会朝着那个方向擦洗
of our mouse cursor at the normal
我们的鼠标光标处于正常状态
playback speed so if we click here now
回放速度 如果我们现在点击这里
it's playing if I go back if I hover
如果我往回走 如果我盘旋 它就会播放
back the playhead follows in Reverse so
向后 播放头紧随其后 因此
it just goes wherever my mouse goes
我的鼠标跑到哪里 它就跑到哪里
[Music]
[音乐]
and if I click and hold with my I'm
如果我点击并按住我的
holding that with my left mouse button
用我的鼠标左键按住它
then I can actually scrub fast or slow
然后我可以快速或缓慢地擦洗
and listen to whatever is happening in
不管发生了什么 你都要倾听
that part of the song so anyway I said
这是这首歌的一部分 所以不管怎样我说
what about playback I don't know if I
回放呢？我不知道如果我
mentioned that in an earlier video or
在之前的视频中提到过 或者
not I'm going to select everything by
不是 我要通过以下方式选择所有内容
double clicking let's go to effects
双击让我们转到效果
there's this phaser effect that gives it
有一种相位器效应给了它
sort of this weird sound if we can bring
如果我们能把这种奇怪的声音
up the options for oh so we can adjust
增加哦的选择 这样我们就可以调整
it and apply it or we can just say start
或者我们可以直接说开始
playback it'll play the music so we can
播放它会播放音乐 这样我们就可以
listen to it and apply these settings as
收听并将这些设置应用为
it's playing so I'm gonna do that so
它在播放 所以我要这么做
this is like a phaser effect if I go to
这就像是相位器效应 如果我去
feedback and make it all the way full
反馈 并让它一直充满
you'll see what it's doing see that and
你会看到它在做什么 看到这一点
then we can change the effects here so
然后我们可以改变这里的效果 这样
we can change how severe that is anyway
无论如何 我们都可以改变这一点的严重性
that's just sort of that phaser effect I
这只是一种相位器效应
didn't apply it but that's the phaser
没有用它 但那是相位器
effect there's this effect called Paul
有一种叫保罗的效应
stretch if we do it we'll just leave
如果我们这样做了 我们就会离开
everything how it is there it kind of
一切都是这样的 有点像
just stretches out and makes your audio
只是伸展一下 让你的音频
really slow it'll it'll make it on much
真的很慢 它会很快的
much longer but it also has this
更长 但它也有这个
interesting effect to it
对它的有趣影响
[Music]
[音乐]
so kind of interesting there's probably
所以很有趣的是 可能有
some interesting things you can do with
一些你可以用来做的有趣的事情
that but these are just kind of fun like
但这些只是一种有趣的感觉
effects you can apply an echo we'll do
您可以应用回声的效果 我们将进行
that in the next video we'll do it some
在下一个视频中 我们将做一些
echo works better with voice and we'll
Echo在语音方面效果更好 我们将
do Equalization the next video - reverb
在下一个视频中实现均衡-混响
kind of gives it a little bit of a echo
给它带来了一点回声
too
太
[Music]
[音乐]
so it's almost like applying an echo and
所以这几乎就像是应用回声和
but we can change you know how it sounds
但我们可以改变你知道这听起来像什么
it almost it's almost like applying an
它几乎就像是在应用一个
echo just keeping that reverb bounce
Echo只是保持着混响反弹
back sound to our audio
将声音返回到我们的音频
another thing similar to that is our I
与此类似的另一件事是我们的i
just thought a bit distortion so we can
只是觉得有点扭曲 这样我们就可以
apply distortion to this so we can
对此应用扭曲 这样我们就可以
actually play back this while we're
在我们播放这段视频的时候
changing it to
将其更改为
[Music]
[音乐]
oh there it is
哦 它在那里
so this is actually pretty much a lot
所以这实际上是相当多的
has a lot of distortion anyway just the
有很大的扭曲 不管怎样 只是
nature of the instruments being used in
所用工具的性质
it but what else effects yeah that's all
但还有什么影响是的 就这些
oh look at this wah
哦 看看这个
which is kind of cool too
这也挺酷的
[Music]
[音乐]
just creates kind of like a wah effect
只是产生了一种像华效应
so there's some different kinds of fun
所以有一些不同的乐趣
effects that we can play with in there I
我们可以发挥的效果
think you get the idea so oh and if we
我想你明白了 所以哦 如果我们
we've got some more down here too by the
我们在这里还有更多的
way
方式
so we'll play some of these later too
所以我们稍后也会播放一些
but just know that you can click on
但只要知道你可以点击
these arrows and you can scroll down and
你可以向下滚动
see other options too that are not
我也看到了其他的选择
necessarily visible depending on your
必要的可见取决于您的
screen resolution so I appreciate you
屏幕分辨率所以我很感激你
watching this video hopefully found
观看这段视频希望发现
informative just kind of a fun one just
信息丰富 只是一种有趣的一个
playing with the effects and getting
玩效果
maybe more familiar with them just so
也许更熟悉他们
you know what tools are available in
你知道有哪些工具可用
case you want to apply them in the
如果你想把它们应用到
future go ahead and like comment
未来继续 喜欢评论
subscribe leave your questions below
订阅在下面留下您的问题
and I hope to see you in the next video
我希望能在下一个视频中看到你